最简单和最常见的摩擦模型称为线性摩擦，有时也称为线性摩擦
The simplest and most common model of friction is called linear friction, sometimes also
称为粘性摩擦或粘性阻尼。然后，力或扭矩成比例
called viscous friction or viscous damping. Then, the force or the torque is proportional
速度。所以，有两种情况。我们可以考虑一个我们有摩擦的线性情况
to velocity. So, there are two cases. We can consider a linear case where we have friction
力与速度成正比，v，或者我们可以将旋转情况与摩擦力相对应
force proportional to velocity, v, or we can have the rotational case where a frictional
扭矩tau与转速omega成正比。如果我们用力量对抗速度，
torque, tau, is proportional to the rotational speed, omega. If we plot force against velocity,
我们可以通过斜率B的直线来表示摩擦的特性并参考
we can represent the characteristic of friction by a straight line of slope B and refer to
B作为摩擦系数。通常，线的斜率为正
B as the friction coefficient. Typically, the slope of the line for positive
和负速度是一样的。这是电流控制电动的模型
and negative velocities is the same. Here is the model for a current controlled electric
我们之前介绍的电机。它将旋转加速度与施加的电流相关联。
motor that we introduced earlier. It relates the rotation acceleration to the applied current.
而且，我将在这里添加摩擦力矩项。而且，摩擦是一个真正的问题
And, I’m going to add a frictional torque term here. And, friction is a real issue in
大多数电动机。摩擦是由于轴在轴内旋转的轴承造成的。
most electric motors. The friction is due to the bearings that the shaft rotates within.
并且，对于带刷子的电动机，这代表了刷子摩擦的摩擦力
And, for motors with brushes this represents the frictional force of the brushes rubbing on
电机的换向器。我可以重新排列方程式
the motor’s Commutator. I can rearrange the equation to look like
这个然后我可以转换它并将其转换为传递函数形式。所以，我们在这里
this and then I can transform it and put it into transfer function form. So, here we
具有电动机的传递功能，并且它包含电动机扭矩
have the transfer function for an electric motor and it incorporates the motor torque
恒定，电机的惯性和电机的摩擦力。一些系统展出
constant, the inertia of the motor and the friction of the motor. Some systems exhibit
非线性摩擦和最经典的情况称为库仑摩擦
a nonlinear friction and the most classic case of this is known as Coulomb friction
这是以一位着名的法国物理学家的名字命名的，他也在静电方面做了很多工作
and this is named after a famous French physicist who also did a lot of work in electrostatics
电荷单位以同一位绅士的名字命名。
and the unit of electric charge is named after this same gentleman.
就像我们之前看到的线性摩擦一样，非线性摩擦力总是相反的
Like the linear friction we looked at before, the nonlinear friction force always opposes
运动的方向。有趣的是，库仑摩擦没有定义
the direction of motion. Interestingly, Coulomb friction is not defined
对于零速度的情况。我们定义机构移动时的摩擦量
for the case of zero velocity. We define the amount of friction when the mechanism is moving
在正方向和机构向负方向移动时，这些
in the positive direction and when the mechanism is moving in the negative direction, and these
值可以相同，也可以不同。这取决于机制。
values may be the same or they may be different. It depends on the mechanism.
对于真正的机器，摩擦实际上是这两种效果的组合，即
For a real machine, friction is actually a combination of both these two effects, the
非线性库仑摩擦和线性摩擦。再次，这个摩擦曲线
nonlinear Coulomb friction and the linear friction. Once again, this friction curve
没有为零速度的情况定义。这两个术语可以相同或不同
is not defined for the case of zero velocity. These two terms may be the same or different
并且正负速度线的斜率可以相同或者相等
and the slope of the line for positive and negative velocities may be the same or it
可能会有所不同。再一次，它取决于特定的机器。
may be different. Once again, it depends on the particular machine.